Sharpe's Rifles is a war, adventure, tv movie film directed by Tom Clegg.
During the Peninsular War in Spain against the French, Sergeant Richard Sharpe saves the life of
Arthur Wellesley, the future Duke of Wellington and is promoted to Lieutenant.
In order to pay the troops Wellesley needs a money draft from the banker Rothschild, but fears he
has been captured by the French and sends Sharpe behind enemy lines to find him.
Sharpe is given command of a platoon of crack riflemen, led by the surly Irishman Harper and
including Hagman and Harris, who resent Sharpe as not being a 'proper officer'.
Richard Sharpe, played by Sean Bean.
Major Michael Hogan, played by Brian Cox.
Patrick Harper, played by Daragh O'Malley.
Comandante Teresa Moreno, played by Assumpta Serna.
Sir Arthur Wellesley, played by David Troughton.
Rifleman Daniel Hagman, played by John Tams.
Sharpe's Rifles is the first of the Sharpe television dramas, based
on Bernard Cornwell's 1988 novel of the same name.
Shown on ITV in 1993, the adaptation stars Sean Bean,
Daragh O'Malley and Assumpta Serna.
It began a long series of successful and critically
acclaimed television adaptations of the novels.
The drama tells the story of Richard Sharpe, an
ambitious and hardened soldier from Yorkshire.
The story follows the exploits of Sharpe and his band of chosen men
through Spain after they survive an ambush by French cavalry.
Filming took place in the Crimea, Portugal and England, during which Paul McGann who was the original actor
cast for the role of Richard Sharpe, broke his leg and was quickly replaced with Sean Bean.